### losif V.

#### Software Engineer

London, UK

in iosify iosify iosify

Hey there I'm Iosif, a senior Backend Engineer with experience in creating complete projects from start to finish in Node.js and PHP. I write code as clean as possible so that the next dev will be happy to maintain it and the junior will quickly grasp it. Curious by nature, I'm always willing to learn new things, so these days I spend my evenings working with Solidity and Hardhat on creating Blockchain smart contracts.

#### SKILLS -

# LanguagesFrameworksAdminNode.jsTypescriptPHPLaravelExpressServerlessAWSTerraformCI / CDSoliditybashHardhatDockerShell Scripting

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE (10)**

Software Engineer at Freelancer

Aug 2020 - Current

https://casa4.co.uk/

Contractor for various clients on different projects & extra work on personal projects

- Currently focusing on blockchain projects. As a side, improving my dev-ops skills and working on some Larayel websites.
- Technologies: Node.js, Hardhat, Solidity, Terraform, PHP, Laravel, Laravel Forge, AWS, VueJS, Nuxt JS, CLI, Bash

**Software Engineer** at True Compliance

Oct 2020 - Aug 2022

Cloud Based Compliance Management System.

- Worked on building the main API of the system. Contributed to all the adjacent applications
  which constituted the entire ecosystem deployed as serverless functions on AWS with Laravel
  Vapor. Involved in designing some parts of the ecosystem's architecture.
- Some notable projects were a full reporting application which would create a report from any SQL provided. A system to serve real time data faster to the end client; by saving all the processed relational data into a no-sql database thus providing instant access to the transformed client-friendly set of the data.
- Technologies: PHP 7, PHP 8, Laravel 8, Laravel 9, Laravel Vapor, AWS, VueJS, Node.js, Serverless Framework, CLI, Bash

#### **Software Engineer** at Freelancer

Oct 2019 - Sep 2020

Contractor for various clients on different projects & extra work on personal projects

- Created a complete invoicing application from design to production. This is reading data from XMLs deployed daily on external FTP servers, then joins and transforms them into beautifully organised information easy to interact with. Built with AWS Lambda functions in Node.js using the Serverless Framework and DynamoDB.
- Technologies: Serverless-Framework, Node.js, TypeScript, Laravel, VueJS, AWS, Lambda, EC2, S3, IAM, RDS, DynamoDB, API Gateway

#### Software Engineer at Skin Analytics

Oct 2018 - Oct 2019

Designing and developing our main Al Skin Analytics applications and keeping an eye on the AWS infrastructure.

- Biggest task was a migration from a no-sql database to a relational database which resulted in a 11x speed increase. All this was achieved with 100% transparency to the end user.
- Technologies: Node.js, Express.js, TypeScript, AWS, Loopback, pm2, Angular

#### **PHP Application Developer** at Freelancer

Jul 2018 - Nov 2018

https://casa4.co.uk/

Worked with various clients on Symfony or Laravel Projects.

- For each client I worked with, I was submitting pull requests in the first day.
- Biggest project was a complex tool-renting platform written in Laravel where I worked in a team of about 20 developers
- Technologies: Laravel 5.6, Symfony, PHP 7.1, MySql, Git, PhpUnit

#### PHP Application Developer / Dev-Ops at Woooba

Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

Designing, developing & supporting client applications.

- Developed & maintained nationwide educational platforms. Designed and integrated various APIs.
- We built a complete financial management application.
- Managed all our DigitalOcean droplets with a CI setup.
- Technologies: Laravel, DigitalOcean, Laravel Forge, PHP 5.6, PHP 7.1, RESTful APIs, MySql, Git, CLI, VueJS, PhpUnit.

#### PHP Application Developer at iQU Group

Nov 2015 - Nov 2016

https://iqu.com/

Marketing solutions for game developers.

- Created complete APIs from start to end as well as libraries which were used by my colleagues.
- Another smaller project was built with Java and PipelineDB.
- Technologies: PHP, Laravel, Symfony, API, MySQL, Git, Docker, CLI, PhpUnit, AngularJS, Java

#### PHP Application Developer at Project 89109

Oct 2014 - Nov 2015

Online adult dating services.

Technologies: PHP, API, MySQL, CLI, Git, JS, jQuery.

Hardware Engineer / Dev-Ops at Hidden Hash (Personal Venture)

Nov 2017 - Current

Family business dealing with mining crypto-currencies.

- Worked on Business model, Hardware setup, Software & security optimization/tweaks/updates,
   Performance fine tuning, Trading generated assets.
- Learned a lot about managing a larger than usual number of computers and hardware components.
- Built an open-source watchdog mechanism for certain types of graphic cards (https://github.com/iosifv/amd-vega-startup-scripts).

#### **Photographer** at Saya Studio (Personal Venture)

May 2005 - Dec 2014

Photography studio focusing mainly on weddings.

 Worked on Client handling, Marketing, Accounting, Management, Photographing, Retouching, Graphic design, Web-design.

## PROJECTS (3) Terminal ToolBelt ☑ https://github.com/iosifv/terminal-toolbelt

- Open source collection of aliases and bash functions which I use.
- Organised in something which resembles a CLI Framework.

#### **Silence**

https://github.com/iosifv/silence

Open source tool for safely backing up ssh keys in a git repository

#### iosifv.com

https://github.com/iosifv/iosifv-copy

- A copy of the repository of my website.
- Backend management system written in Laravel. Includes a photo gallery, quotes collection and a really cool json generated CV.

#### EDUCATION (2) —

Masters Management and Business Engineering at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

2010 - 2012

General management theories

Masters Computer Science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

2004 - 2009



#### INTERESTS

#### **Hobbies**

Chess HiFi Music Photography

#### **REFERENCES**

" https://www.linkedin.com/in/iosifv/ "

**Publicly available on LinkedIn**